Marius Lazar

 Q Romania
 ■ mariuslazar93@yahoo.ro
 □ +447731709279
 ■ https://mariuslazar93.github.io/

SUMMARY

I am a CS graduate with a passion for web development having 4+ years of professional experience working with clients or building in-house projects. Last 5 months I have been on a sabbatical travelling around Southeast Asia, which ended suddenly due to the virus and now I'm looking for a remote position, available to relocate when life is back to normal.

EXPERIENCE

Fullstack Developer

Packt Publishing

December 2017 - November 2019, Birmingham, UK

- · Contributed in the stack upgrade from a monolith to a microservice approach using Serverless Framework with NodeJS on AWS infrastructure which exposed me to Lambda functions, NoSQL databases, Queues, Streams and Cloud Storage systems.
- \cdot Developed end-to-end NodeJS microservices to enable new features for our business.
- · Main contributor in the development and launch of our B2B subscription offering with an Angular 8 microsite and various microservices.
- · Developed CLI tools to solve one-time migrations, reconciliations of failed jobs, creating reports etc.
- · Created/Contributed to reusable NPM packages.
- · Defined a CI and CD pipeline for most of our front-end projects using CircleCI and AWS S3/Cloudfront.
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ Been an advocate for good practices like testing, linting or code reviewing.
- · Helped in the mentoring process of our interns.

Junior Frontend Developer

Packt Publishing

April 2017 - December 2017, Birmingham, UK

- · Main contributor in the maintenance, improvement and redesign of all our 5+ front-ends using AngularJS or Angular 5+.
- · Helped in the process of wrapping our web app into a hybrid app using Cordova API's.
- · Developed an Angular 5 microsite for the purpose of a single authentication/registration point.
- · Integrated our platforms with multiple 3rd parties APIs like GA, Heap, Algolia etc.

Junior Frontend Developer

. Luminos Labs

October 2015 - December 2017, Cluj-Napoca, RO

- · Transforming PSD files into HTML and CSS.
- · Building reusable UI components.
- · Reduced client websites loading times following web performance best practices.
- · Improved the front-end development workflow by adding task runners.

PROJECTS

ScrapeFSO

· A CLI tool for scrapping a media website using NodeJS with Cheerio, Puppeteer and AWS S3.

WhatTheForm

· An accessibility orientated project developed during a hackathon. It uses the Nexmo Voice API and Watson Speech-to-Text API to fill up a usual web form by talking over the phone.

BeOneRetreat

 $\cdot \text{A website for my Church Retreat developed with the purpose of learning how to use GatsbyJS and Netlify}.$

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Science

Technical University of Cluj-Napoca · Cluj-Napoca, RO · 2012 - 2016

SKILLS

HTML/CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Angular, Webpack, NodeJS, Express, Mocha, Sinon, Serverless Framework, AWS, Lambda, DynamoDB, PostgreSQL, CircleCI, Linux, Git